preceden.com 2019-09-22

# Privacy | Preceden

Preceden takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the website available at Preceden.com (the “Website”) and is made available under the Creative Commons Sharealike license. Please read this notice carefully.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Preceden collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Preceden’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Preceden’s visitors use its Website. From time to time, Preceden may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its Website.

Preceden also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Preceden does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to the Website choose to interact with Preceden in ways that require Preceden to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Preceden gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at Preceden.com to provide an email address. Preceden collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Preceden. Preceden does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Preceden does not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided Preceden with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at [help@preceden.com](mailto:help@preceden.com). If Preceden becomes aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information.

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data and email address.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and Place of Processing the Data

### Methods of Processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of this Website (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Legal Basis of Processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

  * Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of * Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
  * provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
  * processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

### Retention Time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

  * Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
  * Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

## The purposes of Processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Managing support and contact requests, Managing contacts and sending messages, Displaying content from external platforms, Handling payments, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Infrastructure monitoring, Advertising and Contacting the User.

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

## Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Advertising

Google AdSense  
Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

### Contacting the User

Mailing list or newsletter  
Personal Data: email address

### Handling Payments

Stripe and PayPal  
Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

PayPal button and widgets  
Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

### Managing Support and Contact Requests

Help Scout  
Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

### Analytics

Google Analytics, MixPanel, Amplitude, and FullStory  
Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

### Displaying Content from External Platforms

Typekit  
Personal Data: Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

### Infrastructure Monitoring

Pingdom  
Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

New Relic  
Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

### Managing Contacts and Sending Messages

Drip  
Personal Data: email address

## The Rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

  * Withdraw their consent at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * Object to processing of their Data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. * * Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * Access their Data. Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * Restrict the processing of their Data. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it.
  * Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller. Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User's consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * Lodge a complaint. Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details About the Right to Object to Processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document.

### How to Exercise These Rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

## Additional Information About Data Collection and Processing

### Legal Action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related Services.

The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information Not Contained in This Policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### How “Do Not Track” Requests are Handled

This Website does not support “Do Not Track” requests.

To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

## Aggregated Statistics

Preceden may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Website. For instance, Preceden may monitor the most popular public timelines on the Preceden.com site to help identify spam. Preceden may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Preceden does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Preceden discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Preceden’s behalf or to provide services available at the Website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the Website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. In addition, in some cases we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Preceden or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Preceden goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Preceden may continue to use your personal and non-personal information only as set forth in this policy. Otherwise, Preceden will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations or as described above, Preceden discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Preceden believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Preceden, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the Preceden Website and have supplied your email address, Preceden may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Preceden and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Preceden takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

For users outside the United States, please note that any personally-identifiable information you enter into the Website will be transferred out of your country and into the United States. You consent to such transfer through your use of the Website. You also warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States.

## Types of Timelines

Preceden enables you specify the privacy settings on the timelines you create.

Timelines can be public (visible to anyone), private (visible only to you), or password-protected (visible to people with a password that you set).

## Links to Third Party Sites

This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by Preceden. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Preceden does not own or control, or employees that Preceden does not manage. The Website contains links to third party websites. Any information you provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. We encourage you to read such privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit. It is the sole responsibility of such third parties to adhere to any applicable restrictions on the disclosure of your personally-identifying information, and Preceden and its affiliates shall not be liable for wrongful use or disclosure of your personally-identifying information by any third party.

## Security

All non-personally-identifying information, potentially personally-identifying and personally identifying-information described above is stored on restricted database servers.

## Ezoic

Preceden uses a service called Ezoic to display ads on some publicly shared timelines belong to free users. 

Read more in our [Ezoic Service Privacy Policy](https://www.preceden.com/privacy/ezoic).

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Preceden may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Preceden’s sole discretion. If we do then we’ll notify you by posting the amended policy on the Website or by emailing you of the nature of the modifications along with a link to the modified document so that you can review it. In all cases, use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

## Contact Us

Owner and Data Controller  
205 S. Academy #6004  
Cary, NC 27519

If you have any questions about this policy or our site in general, please contact us at [help@preceden.com](mailto:help@preceden.com).
